It came from outer space!
The Iron Giant is a animation, science fiction,
family film directed by Brad Bird.
In the small town of Rockwell, Maine in October 1957, a giant metal machine befriends a nine-year-old boy and
ultimately finds its humanity by unselfishly saving people from their own fears and prejudices.
Annie Hughes (voice), played by Jennifer Aniston.
Dean McCoppin (voice), played by Harry Connick Jr..
The Iron Giant (voice), played by Vin Diesel.
Foreman Marv Loach / Floyd Turbeaux (voice), played by James Gammon.
Mrs. Lynley Tensedge (voice), played by Cloris Leachman.
Kent Mansley (voice), played by Christopher McDonald.
The Iron Giant is a 1999 American animated science fiction film
directed by Brad Bird and written by Tim McCanlies.
Loosely based on Ted Hughes's novel, The Iron Man, it features an ensemble cast, including Jennifer Aniston, Harry Connick
Jr., Vin Diesel, James Gammon, Cloris Leachman, John Mahoney, Eli Marienthal, Christopher McDonald and M.
Emmet Walsh.
Set during the Cold War in 1957, the film centers on a young boy named Hogarth Hughes,
who discovers and befriends a giant robot of extraterrestrial origin.
With the help of beatnik artist Dean McCoppin, Hogarth attempts to prevent the United States' military, who
have been alerted by paranoid federal agent Kent Mansley, from finding and vanquishing the Giant.
The film was initially conceived in 1994 as a musical with
the involvement of the Who's Pete Townshend.
In 1996, Bird signed on as director and McCanlies
was hired to write the screenplay.
The film was animated using traditional animation, with computer-generated
imagery used to animate the Iron Giant and other effects.
The crew of the film was understaffed and completed it with half
of the time and budget of other animated features.
Michael Kamen composed the film's score, which was
performed by the Czech Philharmonic.
The Iron Giant premiered at Mann's Chinese Theater in Los Angeles on July
31, 1999, and was released in the United States on August 6.
Although it received critical acclaim, the film significantly underperformed at the box office, grossing $31.7 million against a budget of $50 million, which was attributed to
Warner Bros.' lack of marketing and skepticism towards animated film production following the box office failure of Quest for Camelot in the preceding year.
The film was nominated for several awards, winning
nine Annie Awards out of 15 nominations.
Through home video releases and television syndication, the film garnered a cult following and is widely
regarded as a modern animated classic and one of the greatest animated films of all time.
In 2015, an extended and remastered version of the
film was re-released theatrically.
The film explores themes of friendship, small town, based
on novel or book, self sacrifice, cold war.
The tone is uplifting and emotional and thought_provoking.